二零二四年，山西省初中学业水平考试
英语听力测试。
同学们，大家好，现在是。
视听时间。
Alice, the exam is beginning.
Are you ready?
Of course! believe you can make it!
Thank you! Hope all of us can do the best we can!
视听部分结束。
请同学们做好准备，现在开始正式答题。
一情景反映。
本题共有五个小题，每小题你将听到一组对话，
请从每小题所给的。
B, C, answer I made a hamburger for you.
三幅图片中，选出与你所听到的信息相关联的一项，并在答题卡上将该项
涂黑。
读两遍。
It's really kind of you.
I made a hamburger for you.
Number two, look, the old man is crossing the road.
Let's go and help him.
Look, the old man is crossing the
Number three, Linda, shall we meet in the park?
Good idea! It's a right place for camping.
Linda, shall we meet in the park?
Number four, the girl with glasses is the most hardworking in our class.
She sets a good example to us.
The girl with glasses is the most hardworking in our class.
Number five, how do you often work out problems?
By working in a group.
How do you often work out problems?
Number B, and Number six, the storybook is boring.
二，对话理解。
本题共有五个小题，每小题你将。听到一组对话和一个问题，
请从每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项，并在答题卡上将该项涂黑。
读两遍。
Do you think so, Amy?
I agree with you, Tom, but my little brother Bill likes it.
Question, who likes the storybook?
The storybook is boring.
Do you think so, Amy?
I agree with you, Tom, but my little brother Bill likes it.
who likes the storybook?
Number seven, good evening, madam.
May I help you?
Yes, please. I'd like a table for two adults and three children.
Question, how many people are going for dinner?
Good evening, madam.
May I help you?
Yes, please. I'd like a table for two adults and three children.
Question, how many people are going for dinner?
Number eight, mom, I'm leaving for school.
Look at the black clouds.
Don't forget to take the umbrella.
Question, how will the weather be?
Mom, I'm leaving for school.
Look at the black clouds.
Don't forget to take the umbrella.
how will the weather be?
Number nine, time flies.
We have studied together since grade seven.
I still remember you helped me with my English.
Question, what's the relationship between the two speakers?
Time flies. We have studied together since grade seven.
I still remember you helped me with my English.
Question, what's the relationship between the two speakers?
Number ten, it seems impossible for me to play the piano well.
things are difficult before they easy.
Question, what does the woman mean?
It seems impossible for me to play the piano well.
All things are difficult before they are easy.
Question, what does the woman mean?
三语篇理解。
本题你将听到一个语。
篇，请根据所听内容和所提出的五个问题，从每小题所给的
三个选项中，选出一个最佳选项，并在答题卡上将该项涂黑。
读两遍。
Sam is a young boy.
was good at running.
For him, winning was everything.
One day, Sam was going to take part in a running race.
A large group of people came to watch the race, including the boy's grandpa.
To begin with, Sam had a race with some boys of his age.
He won the race as expected.
He was very happy.
In the second race, some strong men came to compete with
He felt a little nervous.
It was a neck and neck race.
He made special efforts and finished first again.
Sam raised his arms and shouted happily, Who wants to run the third race?
At this time, grandpa went to with two new challengers,
an old lady and a blind man.
What's this? This is not a race.
Sam couldn't understand.
Race, said grandpa.
The race is started.
Sam ran fast to the finishing line when he found the two were left far behind.
Sam thought a little.
Then he ran back and took them to walk slowly and finally crossed the finishing line
together. The crowd joined in their success and cheered for the three.
Grandpa smiled and nodded to
felt he won much more than in any race he has ever run before.
Love always wins.
is a young boy.
He was good at running.
For him, winning was everything.
One day, was going to take part in a running race.
A large group of people came to watch the race, including the boy's grandpa.
To begin with, Sam had a race with some boys of his age.
He won the race as expected.
He was very happy.
In the second race,
some strongman came to compete with
He felt a little nervous.
It was a neck and neck race.
He made special efforts and finished first again.
Sam raised his arms and shouted happily.
Who wants to run the third race?
At this time, Grandpa went to with two new challengers,
an old lady and a blind man.
What's this? This is not race.
Sam couldn't understand.
Race, said Grandpa.
The race is started.
Sam ran fast to the finishing line.
When he found the two were left far behind,
Sam thought a little.
Then he ran back and took them to work slowly and finally crossed the finishing line
together. The crowd joined in their success and cheered for the
Grandpa smiled and nodded to Sam.
Sam felt he won much more than in any race he has ever run before.
Love always wins.
四，听力填。
空。
本题你将听到一个语篇，请根据所听内容
完成下面的句子，并将获取的信息写在答题卡相应的位置上。
每空一词，读两遍。
twice. Living lots of historical marks.
Among them, the Asian crossings like Fong Ling Du,
Da Yu Du and Mao Jing Du are the most important parts.
In the past, people built crossings for their boats to stop.
These crossings made the Yellow River lively and became very important to the trade
between the two sides of the river.
And many moving stories happened at these crossings.
They carried memories and feelings of the local people and became bridges between
cultures of the two sides.
As time goes by, people have more ways to travel.
So the crossings are not as important as before.
But in recent years, Shanxi has worked hard to protect these Asian crossings with
local culture. Thanks to its great efforts, these crossings have become popular
places of interest and got new chances to develop.
The Asian crossings of the Yellow River have experienced the historical changes.
In the future, they will continue to play an important role in Shanxi province.
Good morning, and gentlemen.
Welcome to Shanxi.
I'm your guide today.
Let's start our trip to the ancient Yellow River crossings.
The Yellow River is the mother river of China.
It has run through Shanxi for over 900 kilometers,
leaving lots of historical marks.
Among them, the ancient crossings like Fenglingdu,
Dayudu, and Maojindu are the most important parts.
In the past, people built crossings for their boats to stop.
These crossings made the Yellow River lively and became very important to the trade
between the two sides of the river.
And many moving stories happened at these crossings.
They carried memories and feelings of the local people and became bridges between
cultures of the two sides.
As time goes by, people have more ways to travel, so the crossings are not as
important as before.
But in recent years, Shanxi has worked hard to protect these ancient crossings with
local culture. Thanks to its great efforts,
these crossings have become popular places of interest and got new chances to
develop. The ancient crossings of the Yellow River have experienced the historical
changes. In the future, they will continue to play an important role in Shanxi
province.
听力部分到此结束。